<?xml version"1.0"?>
    <eventIdListings title="Windows Security Events">
    <event>
     <id>1</id> 
      <source>Kernel-EventTracing</source>         
       <description>The backing-file for the real-time session "PCA file tracing session" has reached its maximum size. As a result, new events will not be logged to this session until space becomes available. This error is often caused by starting a trace session in real-time mode without having any real-time consumers.</description>       
     </event>
    
     <id>2</id> 
      <source>Kernel-EventTracing</source>         
       <description>Session __SESSION_NAME__ failed to start with the following error: 0xC000000D</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>3</id>  
      <source>Kernel-EventTracing</source>    
       <description>Session __SESSION_NAME__ stopped due to the following error: 0xC0000188</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>4</id>
      <source>Kernel-EventTracing</source>
       <description>The maximum file size for session __SESSION_NAME__ has been reached. As a result, events might be lost (not logged) to file "C:\windows\system32\LogFiles\<__SESSION_PATH__>". The maximum files size is currently set to __BYTE_SIZE__ bytes.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>9</id>
      <source>Security-Kerberos</source>
       <description>The client has failed to validate the domain controller certificate for [domain controller]. The following error was returned from the certificate validation process: A certificate chain could not be built to a trusted root authority.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>20</id>
      <source>Windows Update Agent</source>
       <description>Installation error. Provides the application the update version that failed to install with the application name, along with stop codes.</description>       
     </event>


    <event>
     <id>21</id>
      <source>HAL</source>
       <description>The hardware real-time clock was not queried because evaluation of the ACPI Time and Alarm Device method failed.  Status: 0xC00000BB.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>36</id>
      <source>Volsnap</source>
       <description>The shadow copies of volume C: were aborted because the shadow copy storage could not grow due to a user imposed limit.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>41</id>
      <source>Kernel-Power</source>
       <description>The system has rebooted without cleanly shutting down first. This error could be caused if the system stopped responding, crashed, or lost power unexpectedly.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>167</id>
     <source>Hyper-V-Hypervisor</source>
      <description>The hypervisor did not enable mitigations for side channel vulnerabilities for virtual machines because HyperThreading is enabled. To enable mitigations for virtual machines, disable HyperThreading.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>196</id>
      <description>
       USB device draining system power when system is idle.                   
       USB Device: VID: 0xBDA PID: 0x8153 REV: 0x3100             
       Removal action failed: SkippedAsPersistentIoObserved
        </description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>201</id>
     <source>DeviceManagement-Enterprise-Diagnostics-Provider</source>
      <description>MDM Session: OMA-DM message failed to be sent. Result: (Unknown Win32 Error code: 0x801901ad).</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>202</id>
     <source>DeviceSetupManager</source>
      <description>The Network List Manager reports no connectivity to the internet.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>219</id>
     <source>Kernel-PnP</source>
      <description>
        The driver \Driver\WUDFRd failed to load.
        Device: PCI\VEN_8086&DEV_A71D&SUBSYS_0CFB1028&REV_01\3&11583659&1&20
        Status: 0xC0000365
      </description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>404</id>
      <source>DeviceManagement-Enterprise-Diagnostics-Provider</source>
       <description>MDM ConfigurationManager: Command failure status. Configuration Source ID: (7F67DD5C-C68B-4216-82F4-990223A5ACDC), Enrollment Name: (MDMDeviceWithAAD), Provider Name: (Policy), Command Type: (Add: from Replace or Add), CSP URI: (./Device/Vendor/MSFT/Policy/ConfigOperations/ADMXInstall/Receiver/Properties/Policy/FakePolicy/Version), Result: (The system cannot find the file specified.).</description>       
     </event>

     <event>
     <id>1000</id>
     <source>Application Error</source>      
      <description>.  
        Faulty application crashings. Provides the application name, version number, time stamp and additional stop codes from Windows environment to review the error in-depth.
      </description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>1022</id>      
      <source>.NET Runtime</source>      
      <description>.NET Runtime version 4.0.30319.0 - There was a failure initializing profiling API attach infrastructure.  This process will not allow a profiler to attach.  HRESULT: 0x80004005.  Process ID (decimal): 22268.  Message ID: [0x2509].</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>1026</id>      
      <source>.NET Runtime</source>      
      <description>.NET Runtime version 4.0.30319.0 - There was a failure initializing profiling API attach infrastructure.  This process will not allow a profiler to attach.  HRESULT: 0x80004005.  Process ID (decimal): 22268.  Message ID: [0x2509].</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>1100</id>
      <knowledge>This is a normal event logged at time of shutdown</knowledge>    
       <description>The event logging service has shut down</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>1101</id>   
      <knowledge>We have observed this event being logged upon restarting Windows after a dirty shutdown.</knowledge>
       <description>Audit events have been dropped by the transport.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>1102</id> 
      <knowledge>
      Criticality: Medium/High — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.
      Event 1102 is logged whenever the Security log is cleared, REGARDLESS of the status of the Audit System Events audit policy. The Account Name and Domain Name fields identify the user who cleared the log.
      Logon ID allows you to correlate backwards to the logon event (4624) as well as with other events logged during the same logon session.
       </knowledge>
       <description>The audit log was cleared</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>1104</id>
     <knowledge>
     No more events will be logged until the log is expanded, cleared or configured to overwrite events.

     This event indicates a "hole" in your audit trail and should be avoided with the implementation of an effective log management solution that collects events before they can be overwritten or before the log fills up.

     "Do not overwrite events (clear log manually)" should only be used in conjunction with the security option "Audit: Shutdown system immediately if unable to log security audits".  Of course these 2 settings together will cause the system outages if the log is allowed to fill up and would only be appropriate for systems with the highest integrity requirements on audit trails.
     </knowledge>      
      <description>The security Log is now full</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>1105</id>  
     <knowledge>
     This event is only logged when "When maximum log size is reached:" is set to "Archive the log when full, do not overwrite events". When the log reaches maximum size Windows saves it to %systemroot%\System32\Winevt\Logs\ with the file name Archive-Security-YYYY-MM-DD-HH-MM-SS-NNN.evtx.
     </knowledge>    
      <description>Event log automatic backup</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>1108</id>    
       <description>The event logging service encountered an error</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4108</id>
      <source>DeviceManagement-Enterprise-Diagnostics-Provider</source>      
       <description>MDM Declared Configuration resource cleanup task failed.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>4227</id>
      <source>Tcpip</source>      
       <description>
       TCP/IP failed to establish an outgoing connection because the selected local endpoint was recently used to connect to the same remote endpoint. This error typically occurs when outgoing connections are opened and closed at a high rate, causing all available local ports to be used and forcing TCP/IP to reuse a local port for an outgoing connection. To minimize the risk of data corruption, the TCP/IP standard requires a minimum time period to elapse between successive connections from a given local endpoint to a given remote endpoint.
        </description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>4618</id>
     <knowledge>
     Potentially high criticality — investigate on first occurrence. Important note: Windows does not log Event ID 4618 by default. This event is only generated when a specific audit policy has been configured in advance to monitor for a defined pattern of security events (set via "Audit: Generate monitored security log events" or an equivalent SACL/monitoring rule in Group Policy). Because most systems leave the relevant GPOs set to Not Configured, 4618 will typically be absent from logs even on systems with otherwise healthy auditing — its absence does not indicate that no matching activity occurred, only that monitoring for it wasn't explicitly enabled. If 4618 does appear, treat it as high-signal: it means a predefined suspicious pattern was deliberately configured and then triggered.
For comprehensive logging, including relevant Event IDs, administrators should configure appropriate audit policies in Computer Configuration\Security Settings\Advanced Audit Policy Configuration and Computer Configuration\Administrative Templates\Windows Components, and other relevant sections of Group Policy. Given these variables, it's essential for organizations to review and, if necessary, adjust their Windows security audit configurations to align with their security and compliance goals. This ensures that significant events are captured in the Windows Event Viewer, effectively supporting security and compliance requirements.
     </knowledge>      
      <description>A monitored security event pattern has occurred.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>4621</id>
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>      
      <description>Administrator recovered system from CrashOnAuditFail. Users who are not administrators will now be allowed to log on. Some auditable activity might not have been recorded.</description>       
     </event> 

    <event>
     <id>4649</id>
      <knowledge>
     This event is logged when Windows detects a Kerberos authentication request that appears to be a replay of a previous request (same authenticator reused within the replay cache window). This is a built-in Kerberos protection and doesn't require special audit policy configuration to trigger — but it does require Kerberos authentication auditing to be enabled and logged in the first place, which itself is not universally on by default depending on version/edition and GPO configuration.
A 4649 event is inherently high-signal: it indicates either a genuine replay attack attempt, or (more commonly in practice) a client/network issue — such as clock skew, ticket caching bugs, or NAT/load-balancer misconfigurations causing duplicate authentication attempts. Because false positives from misconfiguration are common, 4649 findings should be corroborated against source IP, client behavior, and timing before escalating as malicious.
For comprehensive logging, including relevant Event IDs, administrators should configure appropriate audit policies in Computer Configuration\Security Settings\Advanced Audit Policy Configuration and Computer Configuration\Administrative Templates\Windows Components, and other relevant sections of Group Policy. Given these variables, it's essential for organizations to review and, if necessary, adjust their Windows security audit configurations to align with their security and compliance goals. This ensures that significant events are captured in the Windows Event Viewer, effectively supporting security and compliance requirements.
       </knowledge>      
        <description>A replay attack was detected. May be a harmless false positive due to misconfiguration error.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4675</id> 
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>     
       <description>SIDs were filtered.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4692</id>
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>      
       <description>Backup of data protection master key was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4693</id>
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>     
       <description>Recovery of data protection master key was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4706</id>      
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
       <description>A new trust was created to a domain.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4713</id>
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>      
       <description>Kerberos policy was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4714</id>   
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>   
       <description>Encrypted data recovery policy was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4715</id>
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>      
       <description>The audit policy (SACL) on an object was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4716</id>  
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>    
       <description>Trusted domain information was modified.</description>       
     </event>
          
    <event>
     <id>4719</id> 
     <knowledge>Potentially high criticality — investigate on first occurrence.</knowledge>     
      <description>System audit policy was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4724</id>  
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>    
        <description>An attempt was made to reset an account's password.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4727</id>   
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>   
       <description>A security-enabled global group was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4735</id>
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>      
       <description>A security-enabled local group was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4737</id>      
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
       <description>A security-enabled global group was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4739</id> 
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>     
       <description>Domain Policy was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4754</id>   
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>   
       <description>A security-enabled universal group was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4755</id>  
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>    
       <description>A security-enabled universal group was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4764</id> 
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>     
       <description>A security-disabled group was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4764</id>
      <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>      
       <description>A group's type was changed.</description>       
     </event>
 
    <event>
     <id>4765</id>
     <knowledge>Potentially high criticality — investigate on first occurrence.</knowledge>
      <description>SID History was added to an account.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4766</id>      
     <knowledge>Potentially high criticality — investigate on first occurrence.</knowledge>
      <description>An attempt to add SID History to an account failed.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>4780</id>      
      <description>The ACL was set on accounts which are members of administrators groups.</description>       
     </event>
    
    <event>
     <id>4794</id>
     <knowledge>Potentially high criticality — investigate on first occurrence.</knowledge>
      <description>An attempt was made to set the Directory Services Restore Mode.</description>       
     </event>
        
    <event>
     <id>4816</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>RPC detected an integrity violation while decrypting an incoming message.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4865</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A trusted forest information entry was added.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4866</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A trusted forest information entry was removed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4867</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A trusted forest information entry was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4868</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The certificate manager denied a pending certificate request.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4870</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Certificate Services revoked a certificate.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4882</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The security permissions for Certificate Services changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4885</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The audit filter for Certificate Services changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4890</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The certificate manager settings for Certificate Services changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4892</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A property of Certificate Services changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4896</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>One or more rows have been deleted from the certificate database.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>4897</id>      
     <knowledge>Potentially high criticality — investigate on first occurrence.</knowledge>
      <description>Role separation enabled.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4906</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The CrashOnAuditFail value has changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4907</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Auditing settings on object were changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4908</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Special Groups Logon table modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4912</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Per User Audit Policy was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4960</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec dropped an inbound packet that failed an integrity check. If this problem persists, it could indicate a network issue or that packets are being modified in transit to this computer. Verify that the packets sent from the remote computer are the same as those received by this computer. This error might also indicate interoperability problems with other IPsec implementations.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4961</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec dropped an inbound packet that failed a replay check. If this problem persists, it could indicate a replay attack against this computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4962</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec dropped an inbound packet that failed a replay check. The inbound packet had too low a sequence number to ensure it was not a replay.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>4964</id>   
     <knowledge>Potentially high criticality — investigate on first occurrence.</knowledge>
      <description>Special groups have been assigned to a new logon.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>4963</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec dropped an inbound clear text packet that should have been secured. This is usually due to the remote computer changing its IPsec policy without informing this computer. This could also be a spoofing attack attempt.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4965</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec received a packet from a remote computer with an incorrect Security Parameter Index (SPI). This is usually caused by malfunctioning hardware that is corrupting packets. If these errors persist, verify that the packets sent from the remote computer are the same as those received by this computer. This error may also indicate interoperability problems with other IPsec implementations. In that case, if connectivity is not impeded, then these events can be ignored.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4976</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>During Main Mode negotiation, IPsec received an invalid negotiation packet. If this problem persists, it could indicate a network issue or an attempt to modify or replay this negotiation.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4977</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>During Quick Mode negotiation, IPsec received an invalid negotiation packet. If this problem persists, it could indicate a network issue or an attempt to modify or replay this negotiation.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4978</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>During Extended Mode negotiation, IPsec received an invalid negotiation packet. If this problem persists, it could indicate a network issue or an attempt to modify or replay this negotiation.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4983</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>An IPsec Extended Mode negotiation failed. The corresponding Main Mode security association has been deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4984</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>An IPsec Extended Mode negotiation failed. The corresponding Main Mode security association has been deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5027</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service was unable to retrieve the security policy from the local storage. The service will continue enforcing the current policy.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5028</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service was unable to parse the new security policy. The service will continue with currently enforced policy.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5029</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service failed to initialize the driver. The service will continue to enforce the current policy.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5030</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service failed to start.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5035</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Driver failed to start.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5037</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Driver detected critical runtime error. Terminating.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5038</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Code integrity determined that the image hash of a file is not valid. The file could be corrupt due to unauthorized modification or the invalid hash could indicate a potential disk device error.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5120</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>OCSP Responder Service Started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5121</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>OCSP Responder Service Stopped.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5122</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A configuration entry changed in OCSP Responder Service.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5123</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A configuration entry changed in OCSP Responder Service.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5124</id>      
     <knowledge>Potentially high criticality — investigate on first occurrence.</knowledge>
      <description>A security setting was updated on the OCSP Responder Service.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>5376</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Credential Manager credentials were backed up.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5377</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Credential Manager credentials were restored from a backup.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5453</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>An IPsec negotiation with a remote computer failed because the IKE and AuthIP IPsec Keying Modules (IKEEXT) service is not started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5480</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services failed to get the complete list of network interfaces on the computer. This poses a potential security risk because some of the network interfaces may not get the protection provided by the applied IPsec filters. Use the IP Security Monitor snap-in to diagnose the problem.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5483</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services failed to initialize RPC server. IPsec Services could not be started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5484</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services has experienced a critical failure and has been shut down. The shutdown of IPsec Services can put the computer at greater risk of network attack or expose the computer to potential security risks.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5485</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services failed to process some IPsec filters on a plug-and-play event for network interfaces. This poses a potential security risk because some of the network interfaces may not get the protection provided by the applied IPsec filters. Use the IP Security Monitor snap-in to diagnose the problem.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5827</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Netlogon service denied a vulnerable Netlogon secure channel connection from a machine account.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5828</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Netlogon service denied a vulnerable Netlogon secure channel connection using a trust account.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>6145</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>One or more errors occurred while processing security policy in the Group Policy objects.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6273</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server denied access to a user.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6274</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server discarded the request for a user.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6275</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server discarded the accounting request for a user.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6276</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server quarantined a user.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6277</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server granted access to a user but put it on probation because the host did not meet the defined health policy.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6278</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server granted full access to a user because the host met the defined health policy.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6279</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server locked the user account due to repeated failed authentication attempts.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6280</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server unlocked the user account.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>-</id>      
      <description>General account database changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>-</id>      
      <description>Quality of Service Policy changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24586</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>An error was encountered converting volume.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24592</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>An attempt to automatically restart conversion on volume %2 failed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24593</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Metadata write: Volume %2 returning errors while trying to modify metadata. If failures continue, decrypt volume.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24594</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Metadata rebuild: An attempt to write a copy of metadata on volume %2 failed and may appear as disk corruption. If failures continue, decrypt volume.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4608</id>
      <knowledge>4608 is an important security event: Any operating system is essentially defenseless when the operating system is down.</knowledge>      
       <description>Windows is starting up.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4609</id>
     <knowledge>
     Despite the documentation, as of Release candidate 1 this event is not found. Perhaps this is because the event logging service stops first (event 1100). This is funny since the same problem used to happen in NT.  MS fixed it in 2000 and looks like they broke it again at least as of RC1. I haven't been able to produce this event. Have you? If so, please start a discussion (see above) and post a sample along with any comments you may have! Don't forget to sanitize any private information.
     </knowledge>      
      <description>Windows is shutting down.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4610</id>      
      <knowledge>
      Event 4610 is logged once at startup for each authentication package on the system.

      An authentication package is a DLL that encapsulates a given form of authentication, such as NTLM or Kerberos. The Local Security Authority calls into the appropriate authentication package during the logon process to find out if the user is authentic.

      Although a third party can develop an authentication package, few do so, except for smart card and token manufacturers. The only authentication package logged by Windows Server 2008 is C:\Windows\system32\msv1_0.dll : MICROSOFT_AUTHENTICATION_PACKAGE_V1_0 which is just one of the authentication options supported by Windows (See 514 for a list of standard authentication packages on Windows Server 2003). The other authentication options supported by Windows Server 2008 appear to now be part of a larger package called a security package. See 4622.  From MSDN: "A security package that functions as an authentication package and implements the functionality required by SSPI is called a security support provider/authentication package (SSP/AP)."

      The security implication of event 4610, realistically, is low. Although a rogue package could cause great harm by stealing credentials at the time of logon, the effort required in developing and installing a rogue authentication package is significant.
      </knowledge>
       <description>An authentication package has been loaded by the Local Security Authority.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4611</id>  
      <knowledge>
      An occurrence of event 4611 is logged at startup and occasionally afterwards for each logon process on the system.

      A logon process is a trusted part of the operating system and handles the overall logon function for different logon methods including incoming RAS connections, RunAs, interactive logons initiated by CtrlAltDel, and network logons (as in drive mappings).

      Because logon processes are such trusted functions, a rogue logon process would be a devastating security breach--but an improbable one, given the effort and skill required.

      Standard logon processes for Windows Server 2008:
      
      <ul>
       <li>Winlogon</li>
       <li>Schannell</li>
       <li>KSecDD</li>
       <li>Secondary Logon Service (runas)</li>
       <li>IKE</li>
       <li>HTTP.SYS</li>
       <li>SspTest</li>
       <li>dsRole</li>
       <li>DS Replication CredProvConsent (user account control)</li>
      </ul>
    </knowledge>    
        <description>A trusted logon process has been registered with the Local Security Authority.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4612</id> 
      <knowledge>
      This event has not been observed but would indicate that an extremely high period of activity prevented Windows from logging a number of security events. I haven't been able to produce this event. Have you? If so, please start a discussion (see above) and post a sample along with any comments you may have! Don't forget to sanitize any private information.

      Microsoft reports they have tested logging to over 10,000 events per second. However a bottleneck in disk I/O or other resources could also cause a problem.  If you see this event it probably means you are auditing too much.
      </knowledge>     
       <description>Internal resources allocated for the queuing of audit messages have been exhausted, leading to the loss of some audits.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4614</id>
      <knowledge>
      An occurrence of Event 4614 is logged for each notification package on the system.

      Notification packages are DLLs that Windows calls into whenenever a user changes his/her password. The purpose of a notification package is to let you evaluate passwords against your own rules for acceptability. The notification package answers back whether or not the password is acceptable. Notification packages are also used to implement password synchronization systems.

      A rogue notification package would be a devastating security breach because notification packages are supplied with the clear text of the password and are simpler to write and install than authentication packages and logon processes (see 4610, 4611, and 4622).

      Standard notification packages for Windows server 2008:

      <ul>
       <li>scecli</li>
       <li>RASSFM</li>
       <li>WDIGEST</li>
       <li>KDCSVC</li>
       </ul>
      </knowledge>      
       <description>A notification package has been loaded by the Security Account Manager.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4615</id>      
      <knowledge>LPC is used for communication between threads or processes or for communication between kernel mode and user mode components. The communication can be on the same computer between the client and server functions. In 2000 there were several LPC port spoofing vulnerabilities patched for Windows NT.<knowledge>
      <description>Invalid use of LPC port.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4616</id>      
      <knowledge>
      This event indicates the old and new system time as well as who did it as specified in the Subject: section.  Process information shows the program that was used to change the time.  Changing the time manually from the taskbar uses rundll.exe as shown in the example.

      It is routine to see this event where subject is "LOCAL SERVICE", process name is "svchost.exe"  and can be ignored. You will see this event logged twice in a row for whatever reason.

      Events showing a change by an actual user and a process like rundll.exe indicate a time change outside the normal Windows Time Service.

      The format of date/time changes from Win2008 and Win2012 as shown in the examples.
      </knowledge>
       <description>The system time was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4622</id>     
      <knowledge>
      Security packages are yet another type of plug-in that extends security functionality in Windows.  MSDN defines a security package as "The software implementation of a security protocol. Security packages are contained in security support provider DLLs or security support provider/authentication package DLLs." From http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa380130.aspx: Windows operating system supports authentication using security packages that function as both security support providers and as authentication packages. Security packages provide the logon process support services of a Windows authentication package and also provide authentication services to applications by implementing a set of functions that are mapped to the Security Support Provider Interface (SSPI). The security implication of event 4622 realistically, is low. Although a rogue package could cause great harm by stealing credentials at the time of logon, the effort required in developing and installing a rogue security package is significant.
      </knowledge> 
       <description>A security package has been loaded by the Local Security Authority.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4624</id>    
      <knowledge>
      This is a highly valuable event since it documents each and every successful attempt to logon to the local computer regardless of logon type, location of the user or type of account.  You can tie this event to logoff events 4634 and 4647 using Logon ID.

      Win2012 adds the Impersonation Level field as shown in the example.
      </knowledge>    
      <description>An account was successfully logged on.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4625</id>
      <knowledge>This is a useful event because it documents each and every failed attempt to logon to the local computer regardless of logon type, location of the user or type of account.</knowledge>
       <description>An account failed to log on.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4634</id>      
      <description>An account was logged off.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4646</id>      
      <description>IKE DoS-prevention mode started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4647</id>      
      <description>User initiated logoff.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4648</id>      
      <description>A logon was attempted using explicit credentials.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4650</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode security association was established. Extended Mode was not enabled. Certificate authentication was not used.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4651</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode security association was established. Extended Mode was not enabled. A certificate was used for authentication.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4652</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode negotiation failed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4653</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode negotiation failed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4654</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Quick Mode negotiation failed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4655</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode security association ended.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4656</id>      
      <description>A handle to an object was requested.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4657</id>      
      <description>A registry value was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4658</id>      
      <description>The handle to an object was closed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4659</id>      
      <description>A handle to an object was requested with intent to delete.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4660</id>      
      <description>An object was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4661</id>      
      <description>A handle to an object was requested.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4662</id>      
      <description>An operation was performed on an object.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4663</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to access an object.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4664</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to create a hard link.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4665</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to create an application client context.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4666</id>      
      <description>An application attempted an operation.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4667</id>      
      <knowledge>
      This event is logged in connection with Authorization Manager access checks. See <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/secauthz/establishing-a-client-context-with-authorization-manager-in-c--?redirectedfrom=MSDN">Establishing a Client Context with Authorization Manager in C++</a> for more details.
  </knowledge>
       <description>An application client context was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4668</id>      
      <description>An application was initialized.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4670</id>   
      <knowledge>
      Windows logs this event when someone changes the access control list on an object.  The event identifies the object, who changed the permissions and the old an new permissions.

      Of course the object's audit policy must have auditing enabled for "Write DAC"/"Change Permissions" or "Take Ownership" permissions for the user who just modified this object's access control list or a group to which the user belongs.

      Also, this event is logged based on the status of the Object Access subcategory - not the status of "Authorization Policy Change" subcategory. For instance to log this event for file permission changes, the "File System" subcategory must be enabled for success.

      Note the following problem is fixed in more recent versions of Windows. Definitely in Windows 8/2012. Not sure about Win7 and Win2008R2: This event has been observed as above after deleting an access control entry from the file's ACL.  However the event was not logged after simply blocking permission inheritance and copying existing ACEs.  Evidently this event is only logged when the effective permissions are changed not inheritance settings.

      This event is NOT logged when Active Directory object permissions are changed.
  </knowledge>   
       <description>Permissions on an object were changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4671</id>   
     <knowledge>TBS is a part of Trusted Platform Module.</knowledge>   
      <description>An application attempted to access a blocked ordinal through the TBS.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4672</id>    
      <knowledge>
      This event lets you know whenever an account assigned any "administrator equivalent" user rights logs on.  For instance you will see event 4672 in close proximity to logon events (4624) for administrators since administrators have most of these admin-equivalent rights. 

      So, this is a useful right to detecting any "super user" account logons.  Of course this right is logged for any server or applications accounts logging on as a batch job (scheduled task) or system service.  See Logon Type: on event ID 4624.  You can correlate 4672 to 4624 by Logon ID:.

      Note: "User rights" and "privileges" are synonymous terms used interchangeably in Windows.

      Admin-equivalent rights are powerful authorities that allow you to circumvent other security controls in Windows.  Most admin equivalent privileges are intended for services and applications that interact closely with the operating system.  With just a few exceptions, most admin equivalent privileges neither need nor should be granted to human user accounts.

      Some Microsoft documentation puts this in the "Sensitive Privilege Use / Non-Sensitive Privilege Use" subcategory. However our testing finds this in the "Special Logon" Category.
  </knowledge>  
      <description>Special privileges assigned to new logon.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4673</id>      
      <knowledge>
      Event 4673 indicates that the specified user exercised the user right specified in the Privileges field.

      Note: "User rights" and "privileges" are synonymous terms used interchangeably in Windows.

      Some user rights are logged by this event - others by 4674. Still other, ""high-volume"" rights are not logged when they are exercised unless you enable the security option "Audit: Audit the use of Backup and Restore privilege". 

      Unfortunately, Microsoft has overloaded these privileges so that each privilege may govern your authority to perform many different operations and which privilege is required for which operations is not well documented.  Therefore seeing that a privilege was exercised doesn't really tell you much.  In Win2008 this has been improved with better information in the Server: and Service Name: fields.  In general though, I still classify these events as noise.  Microsoft admits: "These are high volume events, which typically do not contain sufficient information to act upon since they do not describe what operation occurred."

      Note: 4673 and 4674 do not log any activity associated with Logon Rights such as the SeNetworkLogonRight. Do not confuse events 4673 and 4674 with events  4717 and 4718 which document rights assignment changes as opposed to the exercise of rights which is the purpose of events 4673 and 4674. 
  </knowledge>
      <description>A privileged service was called.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4674</id>  
      <knowledge>
       Indicates that the specified user exercised the user right specified in the Privileges field.

       Note: "User rights" and "privileges" are synonymous terms used interchangeably in Windows.

       Some user rights are logged by 4674 - others by 4673. Still other, "high-volume" rights are not logged when they are exercised unless you enable the security option "Audit: Audit the use of Backup and Restore privilege". 

       Unfortunately, Microsoft has overloaded these privileges so that each privilege may govern your authority to perform many different operations and which privilege is required for which operations is not well documented.  Therefore seeing that a privilege was exercised doesn't really tell you much.  In Win2008 this has been improved with better information in the Server: and Service Name: fields.  In general though, I still classify these events as noise.  Microsoft admits: "These are high volume events, which typically do not contain sufficient information to act upon since they do not describe what operation occurred."

       Note: 4673 and 4674 do not log any activity associated with Logon Rights such as the SeNetworkLogonRight. Do not confuse events 4673 and 4674 with events 4717 and 4718 which document rights assignment changes as opposed to the exercise of rights which is the purpose of events 4673 and 4674.
  </knowledge>    
      <description>An operation was attempted on a privileged object.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4688</id>  
     <knowledge>
     Event 4688 documents each program that is executed, who the program ran as and the process that started this process.

     When you start a program you are creating a "process" that stays open until the program exits.  This process is identified by the Process ID:.  You can correlate this event to other events by Process ID to determine what the program did while it ran and when it exited (event 4689).
    </knowledge>
      <description>A new process has been created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4689</id> 
     <knowledge>
     Event 4689 documents when a process ends. 

     When you start a program you are creating a "process" that stays open until the program exits.  This process is identified by the Process ID:. 

     You can use this event to tell how long the program ran by correlating it to the earlier 4688 with the same Process ID.
    </knowledge>     
       <description>A process has exited.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4690</id> 
     <knowledge>
     When a program opens an object like a file, it gets a "handle" to that file which it references in subsequent operations on the object.  Windows checks permissions at the time of the open (aka handle request) but not afterwards.  Windows allows you to duplicate a handle and hand it off to another thread or process which then inherits whatever level of access the first program obtained to the object when the program opened.  Therefore a thread impersonating a different user or a process running as a different user could exploit the potentially higher level of access of the first program for that object.  And that apparently is why this event is logged.  Unfortunately this event doesn't seem to provide enough information to determine if the Handle was given to a lower security thread or process.  Consequently I classify this event as noise.

     For an explanation of the fields in this event see events 4688 and 4656.
    </knowledge>
      <description>An attempt was made to duplicate a handle to an object.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4691</id>      
     <knowledge>
      Indirect access to an object was requested.
     </knowledge>
      <description>Indirect access to an object was requested.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4694</id>      
      <description>Protection of auditable protected data was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4695</id>      
      <description>Unprotection of auditable protected data was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4696</id>      
      <description>A primary token was assigned to process.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4697</id>      
      <description>Attempt to install a service.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4698</id>      
      <description>A scheduled task was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4699</id>      
      <description>A scheduled task was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4700</id>      
      <description>A scheduled task was enabled.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4701</id>      
      <description>A scheduled task was disabled.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4702</id>      
      <description>A scheduled task was updated.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4704</id>      
      <description>A user right was assigned.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4705</id>      
      <description>A user right was removed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4707</id>      
      <description>A trust to a domain was removed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4709</id>      
      <description>IPsec Services was started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4710</id>      
      <description>IPsec Services was disabled.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4711</id>      
      <description>May contain any one of the following: PAStore Engine applied locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine applied Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine applied local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to apply locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to apply Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to apply local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to apply some rules of the active IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to load directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine loaded directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to load local storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine loaded local storage IPsec policy on the computer.PAStore Engine polled for changes to the active IPsec policy and detected no changes.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4712</id>      
      <description>IPsec Services encountered a potentially serious failure.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4717</id>      
      <description>System security access was granted to an account.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4718</id>      
      <description>System security access was removed from an account.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4720</id>      
      <description>A user account was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4722</id>      
      <description>A user account was enabled.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4723</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to change an account's password.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4725</id>      
      <description>A user account was disabled.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4726</id>      
      <description>A user account was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4728</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-enabled global group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4729</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-enabled global group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4730</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled global group was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4731</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled local group was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4732</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-enabled local group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4733</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-enabled local group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4734</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled local group was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4738</id>      
      <description>A user account was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4740</id>      
      <description>A user account was locked out.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4741</id>      
      <description>A computer account was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4742</id>      
      <description>A computer account was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4743</id>      
      <description>A computer account was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4744</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled local group was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4745</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled local group was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4746</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-disabled local group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4747</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-disabled local group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4748</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled local group was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4749</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled global group was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4750</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled global group was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4751</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-disabled global group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4752</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-disabled global group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4753</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled global group was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4756</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-enabled universal group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4757</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-enabled universal group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4758</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled universal group was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4759</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled universal group was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4760</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled universal group was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4761</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-disabled universal group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4762</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-disabled universal group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4767</id>      
      <description>A user account was unlocked.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4768</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos authentication ticket (TGT) was requested.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4769</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos service ticket was requested.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4770</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos service ticket was renewed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4771</id>      
      <description>Kerberos pre-authentication failed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4772</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos authentication ticket request failed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4774</id>      
      <description>An account was mapped for logon.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4775</id>      
      <description>An account could not be mapped for logon.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4776</id>      
      <description>The domain controller attempted to validate the credentials for an account.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4777</id>      
      <description>The domain controller failed to validate the credentials for an account.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4778</id>      
      <description>A session was reconnected to a Window Station.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4779</id>      
      <description>A session was disconnected from a Window Station.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4781</id>      
      <description>The name of an account was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4782</id>      
      <description>The password hash an account was accessed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4783</id>      
      <description>A basic application group was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4784</id>      
      <description>A basic application group was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4785</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a basic application group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4786</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a basic application group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4787</id>      
      <description>A nonmember was added to a basic application group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4788</id>      
      <description>A nonmember was removed from a basic application group.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4789</id>      
      <description>A basic application group was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4790</id>      
      <description>An LDAP query group was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4793</id>      
      <description>The Password Policy Checking API was called.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4800</id>      
      <description>The workstation was locked.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4801</id>      
      <description>The workstation was unlocked.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4802</id>      
      <description>The screen saver was invoked.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4803</id>      
      <description>The screen saver was dismissed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4864</id>      
      <description>A namespace collision was detected.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4869</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services received a resubmitted certificate request.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4871</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services received a request to publish the certificate revocation list (CRL).</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4872</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services published the certificate revocation list (CRL).</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4873</id>      
      <description>A certificate request extension changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4874</id>      
      <description>One or more certificate request attributes changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4875</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services received a request to shut down.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4876</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services backup started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4877</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services backup completed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4878</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services restore started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4879</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services restore completed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4880</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4881</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services stopped.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4883</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services retrieved an archived key.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4884</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services imported a certificate into its database.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4886</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services received a certificate request.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4887</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services approved a certificate request and issued a certificate.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4888</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services denied a certificate request.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4889</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services set the status of a certificate request to pending.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4891</id>      
      <description>A configuration entry changed in Certificate Services.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4893</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services archived a key.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4894</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services imported and archived a key.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4895</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services published the CA certificate to Active Directory Domain Services.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4898</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services loaded a template.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4902</id>      
      <description>The Per-user audit policy table was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4904</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to register a security event source.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4905</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to unregister a security event source.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4909</id>      
      <description>The local policy settings for the TBS were changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4910</id>      
      <description>The Group Policy settings for the TBS were changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4928</id>      
      <description>An Active Directory replica source naming context was established.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4929</id>      
      <description>An Active Directory replica source naming context was removed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4930</id>      
      <description>An Active Directory replica source naming context was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4931</id>      
      <description>An Active Directory replica destination naming context was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4932</id>      
      <description>Synchronization of a replica of an Active Directory naming context has begun.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4933</id>      
      <description>Synchronization of a replica of an Active Directory naming context has ended.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4934</id>      
      <description>Attributes of an Active Directory object were replicated.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4935</id>      
      <description>Replication failure begins.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4936</id>      
      <description>Replication failure ends.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4937</id>      
      <description>A lingering object was removed from a replica.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4944</id>      
      <description>The following policy was active when the Windows Firewall started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4945</id>      
      <description>A rule was listed when the Windows Firewall started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4946</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to Windows Firewall exception list. A rule was added.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4947</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to Windows Firewall exception list. A rule was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4948</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to Windows Firewall exception list. A rule was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4949</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall settings were restored to the default values.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4950</id>      
      <description>A Windows Firewall setting has changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4951</id>      
      <description>A rule has been ignored because its major version number was not recognized by Windows Firewall.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4952</id>      
      <description>Parts of a rule have been ignored because its minor version number was not recognized by Windows Firewall. The other parts of the rule will be enforced.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4953</id>      
      <description>A rule has been ignored by Windows Firewall because it could not parse the rule.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4954</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall Group Policy settings have changed. The new settings have been applied.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4956</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall has changed the active profile.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4957</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall did not apply the following rule.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4958</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall did not apply the following rule because the rule referred to items not configured on this computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4979</id>      
      <description>IPsec Main Mode and Extended Mode security associations were established.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4980</id>      
      <description>IPsec Main Mode and Extended Mode security associations were established.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4981</id>      
      <description>IPsec Main Mode and Extended Mode security associations were established.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4982</id>      
      <description>IPsec Main Mode and Extended Mode security associations were established.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4985</id>      
      <description>The state of a transaction has changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5024</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service has started successfully.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5025</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service has been stopped.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5031</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service blocked an application from accepting incoming connections on the network.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5032</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall was unable to notify the user that it blocked an application from accepting incoming connections on the network.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5033</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Driver has started successfully.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5034</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Driver has been stopped.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5039</id>      
      <description>A registry key was virtualized.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5040</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. An Authentication Set was added.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5041</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. An Authentication Set was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5042</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. An Authentication Set was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5043</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Connection Security Rule was added.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5044</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Connection Security Rule was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5045</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Connection Security Rule was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5046</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Crypto Set was added.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5047</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Crypto Set was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5048</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Crypto Set was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5050</id>      
      <description>An attempt to programmatically disable the Windows Firewall using a call to InetFwProfile.FirewallEnabled(False).</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5051</id>      
      <description>A file was virtualized.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5056</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic self test was performed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5057</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic primitive operation failed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5058</id>      
      <description>Key file operation.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5059</id>      
      <description>Key migration operation.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5060</id>      
      <description>Verification operation failed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5061</id>      
      <description>Cryptographic operation.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5062</id>      
      <description>A kernel-mode cryptographic self test was performed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5063</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic provider operation was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5064</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic context operation was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5065</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic context modification was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5066</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function operation was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5067</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function modification was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5068</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function provider operation was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5069</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function property operation was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5070</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function property modification was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5125</id>      
      <description>A request was submitted to the OCSP Responder Service.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5126</id>      
      <description>Signing Certificate was automatically updated by the OCSP Responder Service.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5127</id>      
      <description>The OCSP Revocation Provider successfully updated the revocation information.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5136</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5137</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was created.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5138</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was undeleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5139</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was moved.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5140</id>      
      <description>A network share object was accessed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5141</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5152</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform blocked a packet.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5153</id>      
      <description>A more restrictive Windows Filtering Platform filter has blocked a packet.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5154</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has permitted an application or service to listen on a port for incoming connections.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5155</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has blocked an application or service from listening on a port for incoming connections.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5156</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has allowed a connection.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5157</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has blocked a connection.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5158</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has permitted a bind to a local port.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5159</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has blocked a bind to a local port.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5378</id>      
      <description>The requested credentials delegation was disallowed by policy.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5440</id>      
      <description>The following callout was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5441</id>      
      <description>The following filter was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5442</id>      
      <description>The following provider was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5443</id>      
      <description>The following provider context was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5444</id>      
      <description>The following sublayer was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5446</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform callout has been changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5447</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform filter has been changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5448</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform provider has been changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5449</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform provider context has been changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5450</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform sublayer has been changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5451</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Quick Mode security association was established.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5452</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Quick Mode security association ended.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5456</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine applied Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5457</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to apply Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5458</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine applied locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5459</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to apply locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5460</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine applied local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5461</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to apply local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5462</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to apply some rules of the active IPsec policy on the computer. Use the IP Security Monitor snap-in to diagnose the problem.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5463</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the active IPsec policy and detected no changes.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5464</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the active IPsec policy, detected changes, and applied them to IPsec Services.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5465</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine received a control for forced reloading of IPsec policy and processed the control successfully.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5466</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the Active Directory IPsec policy, determined that Active Directory cannot be reached, and will use the cached copy of the Active Directory IPsec policy instead. Any changes made to the Active Directory IPsec policy since the last poll could not be applied.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5467</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the Active Directory IPsec policy, determined that Active Directory can be reached, and found no changes to the policy. The cached copy of the Active Directory IPsec policy is no longer being used.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5468</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the Active Directory IPsec policy, determined that Active Directory can be reached, found changes to the policy, and applied those changes. The cached copy of the Active Directory IPsec policy is no longer being used.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5471</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine loaded local storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5472</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to load local storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5473</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine loaded directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5474</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to load directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5477</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to add quick mode filter.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5479</id>      
      <description>IPsec Services has been shut down successfully. The shutdown of IPsec Services can put the computer at greater risk of network attack or expose the computer to potential security risks.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5632</id>      
      <description>A request was made to authenticate to a wireless network.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5633</id>      
      <description>A request was made to authenticate to a wired network.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5712</id>      
      <description>A Remote Procedure Call (RPC) was attempted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5888</id>      
      <description>An object in the COM+ Catalog was modified.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5889</id>      
      <description>An object was deleted from the COM+ Catalog.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5890</id>      
      <description>An object was added to the COM+ Catalog.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6008</id>      
      <description>The previous system shutdown was unexpected.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6144</id>      
      <description>Security policy in the Group Policy objects has been applied successfully.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6272</id>      
      <description>Network Policy Server granted access to a user.</description>       
     </event>
     
    
     

     
    <event>
     <id>5049</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Security Association was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5478</id>      
      <description>IPsec Services has started successfully.</description>       
     </event>
     
     
    <event>
     <id>4608</id>      
      <description>Windows is starting up</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4609</id>      
      <description>Windows is shutting down</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4610</id>      
      <description>An authentication package has been loaded by the Local Security Authority</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4611</id>      
      <description>A trusted logon process has been registered with the Local Security Authority</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4612</id>      
      <description>Internal resources allocated for the queuing of audit messages have been exhausted, leading to the loss of some audits.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4614</id>      
      <description>A notification package has been loaded by the Security Account Manager.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4615</id>      
      <description>Invalid use of LPC port</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4616</id>      
      <description>The system time was changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4618</id>      
      <description>A monitored security event pattern has occurred</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4621</id>      
      <description>Administrator recovered system from CrashOnAuditFail</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4622</id>      
      <description>A security package has been loaded by the Local Security Authority.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4624</id>      
      <description>An account was successfully logged on</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4625</id>      
      <description>An account failed to log on</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4626</id>      
      <description>User/Device claims information</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4627</id>      
      <description>Group membership information.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4634</id>      
     <knowledge>Marks the end of a logon session, correlating back to a 4624 (logon) event via the Logon ID. Note: for network connections, users can appear to log on/off many times a day just from idle session termination, and a system shutdown may delay logging this event until the next restart.</knowledge>
      <description>An account was logged off</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4646</id>    
      <knowledge>Related to IPsec Main Mode. This one's rarely seen in practice — even the site notes they haven't been able to produce a real-world example of it.</knowledge>  
      <description>IKE DoS-prevention mode started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4647</id>      
      <knowledge>Logged instead of 4634 for interactive and remote desktop (RDP) logons when a user actively logs off. It's useful because it lets you distinguish a deliberate user logoff from a session just timing out from inactivity.</knowledge>
       <description>User initiated logoff</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4648</id>     
     <knowledge>
      This is a useful event for tracking several different situations:
      <ul>
      <li>A user connects to a server or runs a program locally using alternate credentials.  For instance a user maps a drive to a server but specifies a different user's credentials or opens a shortcut under RunAs by shift-control-right-clicking on the shortcut, selecting Run as..., and then filling in a different user's credentials in the dialog box that appears.  Or a user logs on to a web site using new specific credentials.  That is the case above in the example - Administrator was logged on to the local computer and then accessed a SharePoint server sp01.icemail.com as rsmith@mtg.com.</li>
      <li>This event is also logged when a process logs on as a different account such as when the Scheduled Tasks service starts a task as the specified user. Logged on user: specifies the original user account.</li>
      <li>With User Account Control enabled, an end user runs a program requiring admin authority.  You will get this event where the process information is consent.exe.  Unfortunately Subject does not identify the end user.</li>
      </ul>
     Unfortunately this event is also logged in situations where it doesn't seem necessary.  For instance logging on interactively to a member server (Win2008 RC1) with a domain account produces an instance of this event in addition to 2 instances of 4624.

      </knowledge> 
      <description>A logon was attempted using explicit credentials</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4649</id>      
      <description>A replay attack was detected</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4650</id>  
     <knowledge>An IPsec Main Mode security association was established. Extended Mode was not enabled.  Certificate authentication was not used.</knowledge>    
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode security association was established</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4651</id> 
     <knowledge>An IPsec Main Mode security association was established. Extended Mode was not enabled.  A certificate was used for authentication.</knowledge>     
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode security association was established</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4652</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode negotiation failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4653</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode negotiation failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4654</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Quick Mode negotiation failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4655</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Main Mode security association ended</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4656</id>  
     <knowledge>
     
     This event is logged by multiple subcategories as indicated above.

     When you enable auditing on an object (e.g. file or folder), this is the first event recorded when an application attempts to access the object in such a way that matches the audit policy defined for that object in terms of who is requesting the access and what type of access is being requested. (it appears that two subcategories must be enabled, Handle Manipulation and one other such as File System or Registry depending on what type of object you are auditing.)

     This event will be Audit Success or Audit Failure depending on whether the user account under which the account is running has the requested permissions or not. 

     This event's sub category will vary depending on type of object. In the example above notepad.exe running as Administrator successfully opened "New Text Document.txt" for Read access.

     This event does not always mean any access successfully requested was actually exercised - just that it was successfully obtained (if the event is Audit Success of course).  To determine if any of the permissions requested were actually exercised look forward in the log for 4663 with the same Handle ID.</knowledge>    
      <description>A handle to an object was requested</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4657</id>     
     <knowledge>
     This event documents creation, modification and deletion of registry VALUES.  This event is logged between the open (4656) and close (4658) events for the registry KEY where the value resides.  See Operation Type to find out if the value was created, modified or deleted. Of course this event will only be logged if the key's audit policy is enabled for Set Value permission for the appropriate user or a group in the user is a member.
     </knowledge> 
      <description>A registry value was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4658</id> 
     <knowledge>After successfully opening an object, a program eventually closes it which is documented by this event.  4658 helps you determine how long the object was open. For this event to be useful you must link it back to the earlier event ID 4656 with the same handle ID.</knowledge>  
      <description>The handle to an object was closed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4659</id>  
     <knowledge>
      This event should be logged whenever your install a patch that requires replacement of a file that is already opened by Windows and can't be closed until shut down.

      According to Microsoft it is used by file systems when the FILE_DELETE_ON_CLOSE flag is specified in Createfile(). This flag is the only way to delete files that were opened exclusively by another program.

      The event is listed as a special multi-use sub-category. The sub-category would depend on the type of object being audited.
</knowledge>
      <description>A handle to an object was requested with intent to delete</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4660</id>      
      <knowledge>
      This event is logged by multiple subcategories as indicated above.

      This event is logged when an object is deleted where that object's audit policy has auditing enabled for deletions for the user who just deleted it or a group to which the user belongs.

      To find out the object's name and type you will need to correlate back to to the event 4656 that has the same Handle ID.

      In addition to this event you will also get event 4663 when you delete the object; Accesses: will include DELETE. 4663 identifies the object's name without requiring correlation to 4656.
  </knowledge>

      <description>An object was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4661</id>    
      <knowledge>
      This event is logged by multiple subcategories as indicated above.

      Most objects, when opened (handle request), generate event 4656 but when you open a SAM object you get 4661 instead.

      Some AD objects also double as SAM objects and some properties of those objects double as SAM attributes.  This event is logged when opening such SAM objects such as SAM_DOMAIN or SAM_USER.

      When the object is closed you get event ID 4658 with the same handle ID.

      I regard these events as noise and recommend disabling the SAM subcategory in your audit policy.
  </knowledge>
      <description>A handle to an object was requested</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4662</id>     
       <knowledge>
       Active Directory logs this event when a user accesses an AD object. 

       Of course the object's audit policy must be enabled for the permissions requested and the user requesting it or a group to which that user belongs.

       For tracking property level changes to AD objects I recommend using Directory Service Change events (5136...) instead of this event because 5136, etc provide much better information. 

       On the other hand this is the only event that reports accesses defined for auditing that do not qualify as property changes. 

       For instance changing the permissions on an OU such as for delegating administrative authority requires the WRITE_DAC permission which would get logged by this event.

       Of course I don't recommend auditing read only accesses on AD objects since the value is questionable and would typically generate many, many events.  So on the whole I regard this event as noise and recommend disabling the "Directory Service Access" subcategory in your audit policy on domain controllers.
  </knowledge>
      <description>An operation was performed on an object</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4663</id>      
      <knowledge>
      This event is logged by multiple subcategories as indicated above.

      This event documents actual operations performed against files and other objects.  This event is logged between the open (4656) and close (4658) events for the object being opened and can be correlated to those events via Handle ID. 

      While event 4656 tells you when the object is initially opened and what type of access was requested at that time; 4656 doesn't give you positive confirmation any of the access permissions were actually exercised.  That is the role of this event.  This event, 4663, is logged the first time one or more of the requested permissions are actually exercised.  If the program repeatedly exercises a permission while the object is open, Windows only logs 4663 the first time.

      Note events 4656 and 4658 will not appear unless the subcategory "Handle Manipulation" is enabled along with the target sub-category. Microsoft explains that this was done to make it more difficult to enable these noisy events. They feel the event 4663 is better.

      Win2012 adds Resource Attributes.
  </knowledge>
       <description>An attempt was made to access an object</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4664</id>   
      <knowledge>
      An attempt was made to create a hard link.

      A hard link is a pointer to a file on the same system.
  </knowledge>   
       <description>An attempt was made to create a hard link</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4665</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to create an application client context.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4666</id>      
      <description>An application attempted an operation</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4667</id>  
          <knowledge>
          This event is logged in connection with Authorization Manager access checks. See <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/secauthz/establishing-a-client-context-with-authorization-manager-in-c--?redirectedfrom=MSDN">Establishing a Client Context with Authorization Manager in C++</a> for more details.
  </knowledge>
      <description>An application client context was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4668</id>      
      <description>An application was initialized</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4670</id>      
      <description>Permissions on an object were changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4671</id>      
      <description>An application attempted to access a blocked ordinal through the TBS</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4672</id>      
      <description>Special privileges assigned to new logon</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4673</id>      
      <description>A privileged service was called</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4674</id>      
      <description>An operation was attempted on a privileged object</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4675</id>      
      <description>SIDs were filtered</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4688</id>      
      <description>A new process has been created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4689</id>      
      <description>A process has exited</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4690</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to duplicate a handle to an object</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4691</id>      
      <description>Indirect access to an object was requested</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4692</id> 
      <knowledge>
      Microsoft documentation indicates this is a routine event that can be filtered out of events to review.  At this time I classify this as a "noise" event.
  </knowledge>   
      <description>Backup of data protection master key was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4693</id>      
      <description>Recovery of data protection master key was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4694</id>      
      <description>Protection of auditable protected data was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4695</id>   
     <knowledge>
     This event has to do with the Data Protection API. 

     Per Microsoft: "The Data Protection API (DPAPI) helps to protect data in Windows 2000 and later operating systems. DPAPI is used to help protect private keys, stored credentials (in Windows XP and later), and other confidential information that the operating system or a program wants to keep confidential. "

     Apparently a program running under the account documented in Subject: tried to decrypt a blob with the CryptUnprotectData function and failed.  Status code 0x8009000b is pretty general.  Most often it means 

    <ul>
      <li>The user password has changed and the automatic reprocessing of keys based on user password failed</li>
      <li>The blob was encrypted by a different user than the one now trying to decrypt it.</li>
      </ul>

     So it's possible that that this event could indicate malicious behavior but I've seen it logged during the course of normal operation on a clean, isolated test system too.
     </knowledge>
      <description>Unprotection of auditable protected data was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4696</id>  
      <knowledge>
     This often happens when a service starts or a scheduled task starts under the authority of a different user. You will see events 4624 and 4648 as well as 4776 or 4768 earlier in the log.

     The Assigning process fields identify the process that started the child (new) process. Process ID allows you to link this event to the corresponding event 4688 (process start of the parent process) but there is little need since this event gives you the program name (Process Name) and the user under which the process was running (Subject). 

     Target Process: information identifies the new child process that was started under the account and logon session in New Token Information. 

     You can use the Target Process ID to link back to the earlier 4688 for the new child process ID but again there is little need to do this since you have the Target Process Name: right here in this event.
     </knowledge>    
       <description>A primary token was assigned to process</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4697</id>    
     <knowledge>
     A new service was installed by the user indicated in the subject.  Subject often identifies the local system (SYSTEM) for services installed as part of native Windows components and therefore you can't determine who actually initiated the installation.

     This is a key change control event as new services are significant extensions of the software running on a server and the roles it performs.

     This event is no longer generated on Windows Server 2012r2 and earlier.  The minimum OS version is Server 2016 or Windows 10.
     </knowledge>
      <description>A service was installed in the system</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4698</id>   
     <knowledge>
     The user indicated in Subject: just created a new scheduled task (Start menu\Accessories\System Tools\Task Scheduler) identified by Task Name:.

     This is an important change control event.  See related events for changes to Scheduled Tasks: 4699, 4700, 4701, 4702. 
     </knowledge>   
      <description>A scheduled task was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4699</id>     
     <knowledge>
     The user indicated in Subject: just deleted the scheduled task (Start menu\Accessories\System Tools\Task Scheduler) identified by Task Name:.

     This is an important change control event.  See related events for changes to Scheduled Tasks: 4698, 4700, 4701, and 4702.
     </knowledge> 
      <description>A scheduled task was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4700</id>  
     <knowledge>
     The user indicated in Subject: just enabled the scheduled task (Start menu\Accessories\System Tools\Task Scheduler) identified by Task Name.

     A task must be enabled in order to run at its scheduled time.

     This is an important change control event.  See related events for changes to Scheduled Tasks: 4698, 4699, 4601 and 4702.
     </knowledge>    
      <description>A scheduled task was enabled</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4701</id>    
     <knowledge>
     The user indicated in Subject: just disabled the scheduled task (Start menu\Accessories\System Tools\Task Scheduler) identified by Task Name:.

     In its disabled the state the task will not run at its scheduled time until re-enabled.

     This is an important change control event.  See related events for changes to Scheduled Tasks: 4698, 4699, 4700, 4702
     </knowledge>  
      <description>A scheduled task was disabled</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4702</id>  
     <knowledge>
     The user indicated in Subject: just updated the scheduled task (Start menu\Accessories\System Tools\Task Scheduler) identified by Task Name:.

     This event logs all updates to Scheduled Tasks except for enable and disable operations which have their own events.

     This is an important change control event.  See related events for changes to Scheduled Tasks: 4698, 4699, 4700 and 4701.
     </knowledge>    
      <description>A scheduled task was updated</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4703</id>  
       <description>A token right was adjusted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4704</id>  
     <knowledge>
     This event documents a change to user right assignments on this computer including the right and user or group that received the new right.

     Note: "User rights" and "privileges" are synonymous terms used interchangeably in Windows.

     Rights, like most other security settings, are defined in group policy objects and applied by the computer. Therefore this event will normally show the Assigned By user as the system itself. To determine who actually made the rights assignment change you must search the domain controllers' security logs for changes to groupPolicyContainer objects (logged by Directory Service auditing).

     Logon ID allows you to link this event to the prior event 4624 logon event of the user who performed this action.

     Note: This event, 4704, and 4705 do not log changes to logon rights such as "Access this computer from the network" or "Logon as a service". See events 4717 and 4718. 

     See <b>User Rights</b> table for more information.
     </knowledge>   
      <description>A user right was assigned</description>      
       <table xlink:type="simple"
              xlink:href="images/user-rights-table.png"
              xlink:title=" Windows Security Log Event ID - 4704 User Rights Table"
              xlink:show="embed"
              xlink:actuate="onLoad" />

     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4705</id>
     <knowledge>
     This event documents a change to user right assignments on this computer including the right and user or group that lost the right.

     Note: "User rights" and "privileges" are synonymous terms used interchangeably in Windows.

     Rights, like most other security settings, are defined in group policy objects and applied by the computer. Therefore this event will normally show the Assigned By user as the system itself. To determine who actually made the rights assignment change you must search the domain controllers' security logs for changes to groupPolicyContainer objects (logged by Directory Service auditing).

     Logon ID allows you to link this event to the prior event 4624 logon event of the user who performed this action.

     Note: This event, 4705, and 4704 do not log changes to logon rights such as "Access this computer from the network" or "Logon as a service". See events 4714 and 4718. 

     <b>Subject</b>
     The ID and logon session of the user that revoked the right.  Unfortunately this is just the local system account - see above. 

      <ul>
      <li>Security ID:  The SID of the account.</li>
      <li>Account Name: The account logon name.</li>
      <li>Account Domain: The domain or - in the case of local accounts - computer name.</li>
      <li>Logon ID is a semi-unique (unique between reboots) number that identifies the logon session.  Logon ID allows you to correlate backwards to the logon event (4624) as well as with other events logged during the same logon session.</li>
      </ul>
     </knowledge>      
      <description>A user right was removed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4706</id>      
      <knowledge>
      This event is logged for all new trust relationships connecting to this domain.  While the description says "Trusted" this event applies to both trusted and trusting relationships as documented by Trust Information:

      <b>Subject:</b>

      The ID and logon session of the user that excercised created the trust. 

        <ul>
          <li>Security ID:  The SID of the account.</li>
          <li>Account Name: The account logon name.</li>
          <li>Account Domain: The domain or - in the case of local accounts - computer name.</li>
          <li>Logon ID is a semi-unique (unique between reboots) number that identifies the logon session.  Logon ID allows you to correlate backwards to the logon event (4624) as well as with other events logged during the same logon session.</li>
        </ul>
      </knowledge>
      <description>A new trust was created to a domain</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4707</id>    
     <knowledge>
     This event is logged for all deleted trust relationships that connected to this domain.  While the description says "Trusted" this event applies to both trusted and trusting relationships as documented by Trust Information:

     <b>Subject:</b>

     The ID and logon session of the user that excercised deleted the trust.
     
     <ul>
          <li>Security ID:  The SID of the account.</li>
          <li>Account Name: The account logon name.</li>
          <li>Account Domain: The domain or - in the case of local accounts - computer name.</li>
          <li>Logon ID is a semi-unique (unique between reboots) number that identifies the logon session.  Logon ID allows you to correlate backwards to the logon event (4624) as well as with other events logged during the same logon session.</li>
        </ul>
     </knowledge>
      <description>A trust to a domain was removed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4709</id>      
     <knowledge>
     This event is not produced in the default configuration (using Windows Firewall) however event 5478 is produced..

     Microsoft comments: "This service provides compatibility with Internet Protocol security (IPsec) policies used in earlier versions of Windows...This is a normal condition. No further action is required."
     </knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services was started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4710</id>    
     <knowledge>
     In the default configuration this event is not produced when the IPsec Policy agent service is disabled or fails to start.

     According to Microsoft, "This service provides compatibility with Internet Protocol security (IPsec) policies used in earlier versions of Windows. New deployments of Windows Vista and Windows Server 2008 should not use the policies supported by the IPsec Policy Agent service"

     </knowledge>  
      <description>IPsec Services was disabled</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4711</id>      
      <knowledge>
       	May contain any one of the following: PAStore Engine applied locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine applied Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine applied local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to apply locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to apply Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to apply local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to apply some rules of the active IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to load directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine loaded directory storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine failed to load local storage IPsec policy on the computer. PAStore Engine loaded local storage IPsec policy on the computer.PAStore Engine polled for changes to the active IPsec policy and detected no changes.

      <ul>
        <li>PAStore Engine applied locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine applied Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine applied local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine failed to apply locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine failed to apply Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine failed to apply local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine failed to apply some rules of the active IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine failed to load directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine loaded directory storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine failed to load local storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine loaded local storage IPsec policy on the computer.</li>
        <li>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the active IPsec policy and detected no changes.</li>
</ul>
  </knowledge>
       <description>PAStore Engine (1%)</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4712</id>  
       <knowledge>
      IPsec Services encountered a potentially serious failure.

      In theory this reports when the service cannot perform its required tasks, such as properly processing filters, or cannot protect traffic sent or received by one or more of the network adapters attached to the computer.

      Microsoft suggests restarting the computer to resolve this problem.
    </knowledge>   
       <description>IPsec Services encountered a potentially serious failure</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4713</id> 
     <knowledge>
     Windows logs 4713 when it detects a change to the the domain's Kerberos policy. Kerberos policy is defined in GPOs linked to the root of the domain under Computer Configuration\Windows Settings\Security Settings\Account Policy\Kerberos Policy.

     Unfortunately the Subject fields don't identify who actually changed the policy because Kerberos policy isn't directly configured by administrators. Instead it is edited in a group policy object which then gets applied to the computer. Therefore this event always shows the local computer as the one who changed the policy since the computer is the security principal under which gpupdate runs. 

     <b>Subject:</b>
     
     The ID and logon session of the user that changed the policy - always the local system - see note above.

    <ul>
      <li>Security ID: The SID of the account.</li>
      <li>Account Name: The account logon name.</li>
      <li>Account Domain: The domain or - in the case of local accounts - computer name.</li>
      <li>Logon ID is a semi-unique (unique between reboots) number that identifies the logon session. Logon ID allows you to correlate backwards to the logon event (<a href="https://www.ultimatewindowssecurity.com/securitylog/encyclopedia/event.aspx?eventID=4624">4624</a>) as well as with other events logged during the same logon session.</li>
    </ul>
    </knowledge>
      <description>Kerberos policy was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4714</id> 
     <knowledge>
     This computer's Security Settings\Public Key Policies\Encrypting File System data recovery agent policy was modified - either via Local Security Policy or Group Policy in Active Directory.

     Unfortunately the Subject fields don't identify who actually changed the policy because this policy isn't directly configured by administrators. Instead it is edited in a group policy object which then gets applied to the computer. Therefore this event always shows the local computer as the one who changed the policy since the computer is the security principal under which gpupdate runs. Subject:

     The ID and logon session of the user that changed the policy - always the local system - see note above.

     <ul>
      <li>Security ID: The SID of the account.</li>
      <li>Account Name: The account logon name.</li>
      <li>Account Domain: The domain or - in the case of local accounts - computer name.</li>
      <li>Logon ID is a semi-unique (unique between reboots) number that identifies the logon session. Logon ID allows you to correlate backwards to the logon event (<a href="https://www.ultimatewindowssecurity.com/securitylog/encyclopedia/event.aspx?eventID=4624">4624</a>) as well as with other events logged during the same logon session.</li>
        </ul>
     </knowledge>     
      <description>Encrypted data recovery policy was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4715</id>   
     <knowledge>
     The description is poorly worded but this event is logged whenever you set the security descriptor used to delegate access to the audit policy. You can delegate authority to the system's audit policy using "auditpol /sd:".

     According to Microsoft, this event is always logged when an audit policy is disabled, regardless of the "Audit Policy Change" sub-category setting. This and several other events can help identify when someone attempts to disable auditing to cover their tracks. 
     </knowledge>   
      <description>The audit policy (SACL) on an object was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4716</id>  
     <knowledge>
     This event is logged for modifications to trust relationships connecting to this domain. While the description says "Trusted" this event applies to both trusted and trusting relationships as documented by Trust Information.

     <h3>Subject</h3>
<p>The ID and logon session of the user that exercised modified the trust.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Security ID: The SID of the account.</li>
  <li>Account Name: The account logon name.</li>
  <li>Account Domain: The domain or - in the case of local accounts - computer name.</li>
  <li>Logon ID is a semi-unique (unique between reboots) number that identifies the logon session. Logon ID allows you to correlate backwards to the logon event (<a href="https://www.ultimatewindowssecurity.com/securitylog/encyclopedia/event.aspx?eventID=4624">4624</a>) as well as with other events logged during the same logon session.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Trusted Domain</h3>
<p>The other domain in this trust relationship which despite the word "Trusted" may be a trusting or trusted domain or both. See Trust Information.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Domain Name: the DNS name of the domain</li>
  <li>Domain ID: the pre-Win2k (NetBIOS) name of the domain</li>
</ul>

<h3>New Trust Information</h3>
<p>All the information that defines the type of trust after this change, whether it is one way or mutual, transitivity, etc.</p>

<h4>Trust Type</h4>
<table border="1" cellpadding="4" cellspacing="0">
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Value</th>
      <th>Name</th>
      <th>Description</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>TRUST_TYPE_DOWNLEVEL</td>
      <td>The other domain is pre-Win2k (NTLM only supported)</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>TRUST_TYPE_UPLEVEL</td>
      <td>The other domain is Win2k or later (Windows Kerberos supported)</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>3</td>
      <td>TRUST_TYPE_MIT</td>
      <td>Other domain is actually an MIT Kerberos Realm (probably UNIX)</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>4</td>
      <td>TRUST_TYPE_DCE</td>
      <td>The trusted domain is a DCE realm</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4>Trust Direction</h4>
<table border="1" cellpadding="4" cellspacing="0">
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Direction</th>
      <th>Value</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Disabled</td>
      <td>0x0</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Inbound</td>
      <td>0x1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Outbound</td>
      <td>0x2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Bidirectional</td>
      <td>0x3</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4>Trust Attributes</h4>
<p>A bitwise value comprised of any of the following:</p>
<ul>
  <li>TRUST_ATTRIBUTE_NON_TRANSITIVE: 1</li>
  <li>TRUST_ATTRIBUTE_UPLEVEL_ONLY: 2</li>
  <li>TRUST_ATTRIBUTE_FILTER_SIDS: 4</li>
  <li>TRUST_ATTRIBUTE_FOREST_TRANSITIVE: 8</li>
</ul>

<h4>SID Filtering</h4>
<p>Enabled (always enabled for domains within the same forest). See <a href="http://technet2.microsoft.com/windowsserver/en/library/01e5cf71-b317-4967-82a2-75b7b632b7461033.mspx?mfr=true">Microsoft TechNet</a> for more information.</p>
     </knowledge>    
      <description>Trusted domain information was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4717</id>  
     <knowledge>
     This event documents the grant of logon rights such as "Access this computer from the network" or "Logon as a service".

     Rights, like most other security settings, are defined in group policy objects and applied by the computer. Therefore this event will normally show the Assigned By user as the system itself. To determine who actually made the rights assignment change you must search the domain controllers' security logs for changes to groupPolicyContainer objects (logged by Directory Service auditing). Logon ID allows you to link this event to the prior event 4624 logon event of the user who performed this action.

     This event, 4717, documents the system name for each logon right as opposed to the more familiar description.

     Note: This event and 4718 log changes to strictly logon rights such as "Access this computer from the network" or "Logon as a service" - not to other rights such as "Change the system time" or "Take ownership of files and other objects". See events 4704 and 4705. 

     See image for more details.
     </knowledge>    
      <image xlink:type="simple"
           xlink:href="images/Windows Security Log Event ID 4717 - Logon-Rights.png"
           xlink:title="Windows Security Log Event ID 4717 Logon Rights"
           xlink:show="embed"
           xlink:actuate="onLoad" />
        <description>System security access was granted to an account</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4718</id>
     <knowledge>
     This event documents the revokation of logon rights such as "Access this computer from the network" or "Logon as a service".

     Rights, like most other security settings, are defined in group policy objects and applied by the computer. Therefore this event will normally show the Assigned By user as the system itself. To determine who actually made the rights assignment change you must search the domain controllers' security logs for changes to groupPolicyContainer objects (logged by Directory Service auditing). Logon ID allows you to link this event to the prior event 4624 logon event of the user who performed this action.

     This event, 4718 documents the system name for each logon right as opposed to the more familiar description. Click here for a cross reference.

     Note: This event and 4717 log changes to strictly logon rights such as "Access this computer from the network" or "Logon as a service" - not to other rights such as "Change the system time" or "Take ownership of files and other objects". See events 4704 and 4705.
     </knowledge>      
      <description>System security access was removed from an account</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4719</id>    
     <knowledge>
      This computer's system level audit policy was modified - either via Local Security Policy, Group Policy in Active Directory or the audipol command.

      According to Microsoft, this event is always logged when an audit policy is disabled, regardless of the "Audit Policy Change" sub-category setting. This and several other events can help identify when someone attempts to disable auditing to cover their tracks.

      If group policy was used to configure audit policy unfortunately the Subject fields don't identify who actually changed the policy.  In such cases this event always shows the local computer as the one who changed the policy since the computer is the security principal under which gpupdate runs.

      If auditpol was used to configure audit policy will properly reflect the user in Subject:

      <b>Subject:</b>

      The ID and logon session of the user that changed the policy - always the local system - see note above. 

      <ul>
        <li>Security ID: The SID of the account.</li>
        <li>Account Name: The account logon name.</li>
        <li>Account Domain: The domain or - in the case of local accounts - computer name.</li>
        <li>Logon ID is a semi-unique (unique between reboots) number that identifies the logon session. Logon ID allows you to correlate backwards to the logon event (<a href="https://www.ultimatewindowssecurity.com/securitylog/encyclopedia/event.aspx?eventID=4624">4624</a>) as well as with other events logged during the same logon session.</li>
      </ul>

      <h3>Audit Policy Change</h3>

<h4>Category</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Account Logon</li>
  <li>Account Management</li>
  <li>Detailed Tracking</li>
  <li>Directory Service</li>
  <li>Logon/Logoff</li>
  <li>Object Access</li>
  <li>Policy Change</li>
  <li>Privilege Use</li>
  <li>System Events</li>
</ul>

<h4>Subcategory</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Security State Change</li>
  <li>Security System Extension</li>
  <li>System Integrity</li>
  <li>IPsec Driver</li>
  <li>Other System Events</li>
  <li>Logon</li>
  <li>Logoff</li>
  <li>Account Lockout</li>
  <li>IPsec Main Mode</li>
  <li>Special Logon</li>
  <li>IPsec Quick Mode</li>
  <li>IPsec Extended Mode</li>
  <li>Other Logon/Logoff Events</li>
  <li>Network Policy Server</li>
  <li>File System</li>
  <li>Registry</li>
  <li>Kernel Object</li>
  <li>SAM</li>
  <li>Other Object Access Events</li>
  <li>Certification Services</li>
  <li>Application Generated</li>
  <li>Handle Manipulation</li>
  <li>File Share</li>
  <li>Filtering Platform Packet Drop</li>
  <li>Filtering Platform Connection</li>
  <li>Sensitive Privilege Use</li>
  <li>Non Sensitive Privilege Use</li>
  <li>Other Privilege Use Events</li>
  <li>Process Creation</li>
  <li>Process Termination</li>
  <li>DPAPI Activity</li>
  <li>RPC Events</li>
  <li>Audit Policy Change</li>
  <li>Authentication Policy Change</li>
  <li>Authorization Policy Change</li>
  <li>MPSSVC Rule-Level Policy Change</li>
  <li>Filtering Platform Policy Change</li>
  <li>Other Policy Change Events</li>
  <li>User Account Management</li>
  <li>Computer Account Management</li>
  <li>Security Group Management</li>
  <li>Distribution Group Management</li>
  <li>Application Group Management</li>
  <li>Other Account Management Events</li>
  <li>Directory Service Access</li>
  <li>Directory Service Changes</li>
  <li>Directory Service Replication</li>
  <li>Detailed Directory Service Replication</li>
  <li>Credential Validation</li>
  <li>Kerberos Service Ticket Operations</li>
  <li>Other Account Logon Events</li>
  <li>Kerberos Authentication Service</li>
  <li>Subcategory GUID: the globally unique identifier of the subcategory</li>
</ul>

<h4>Changes</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Failure added</li>
  <li>Failure moved</li>
  <li>Success added</li>
  <li>Success removed</li>
</ul>

     </knowledge>  
      <description>System audit policy was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4720</id>    
     <knowledge>
     The user identified by Subject: created the user identified by New Account:. 

    Attributes show some of the properties that were set at the time the account was created.  Notice account is initially disabled.

    This event is logged both for local SAM accounts and domain accounts.

    You will see a series of other User Account Management events after this event as the remaining properties are punched down, password set and account finally enabled.
     </knowledge>  
      <description>A user account was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4722</id>      
     <knowledge>
     The user identified by Subject: enabed the user identified by Target Account:. 

    This event is logged both for local SAM accounts and domain accounts.

    This event is always logged after event 4720 - user account creation.

    You will also see event ID 4738 informing you of the same information.
     </knowledge>
      <description>A user account was enabled</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4723</id>  
     <knowledge>
      The user attempted to change his/her own password.  Subject and Target should always match.  Don't confuse this event with 4724.

      This event is logged as a failure if his new password fails to meet the password policy.

      If the user fails to correctly enter his old password this event is not logged.  Instead, for domain accounts, a 4771 is logged with kadmin/changepw as the service name.

      This event is logged both for local SAM accounts and domain accounts.

      You will also see event ID 4738 informing you of the same information.
     </knowledge>    
      <description>An attempt was made to change an account's password</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4724</id>   
     <knowledge>
     The Subject attempted to reset the password of the Target:  

      Don't confuse this event with 4723.

      This event is logged as a failure if the new password fails to meet the password policy.

      This event is logged both for local SAM accounts and domain accounts.

      You will also see one or more event ID 4738s informing you of the same information.
     </knowledge>   
      <description>An attempt was made to reset an accounts password</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4725</id>    
     <knowledge>
      The user identified by Subject: disabled the user identified by Target Account:. 

      This event is logged both for local SAM accounts and domain accounts.

      You will also see event ID4738 informing you of the same information.
     </knowledge>  
      <description>A user account was disabled</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4726</id> 
     <knowledge>
      The user identified by Subject: deleted the user identified by Target Account:. 

      This event is logged both for local SAM accounts and domain accounts.

      You will also see event ID 4738 informing you of the same information.
     </knowledge>     
      <description>A user account was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4727</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled global group was created</description>     
      <knowledge>
        The user in Subject: just created a Security Global group identified in New Group.

        In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

        Global means the group can be granted access in any trusting domain but may only have members from its own domain.

        This event is only logged on domain controllers.
      </knowledge>  
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4728</id>      
     <knowledge>
      The user in Subject: added the user/group/computer in Member: to the Security Global group in Group:.

      In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

      Global means the group can be granted access in any trusting domain but may only have members from its own domain. 

      This event is only logged on domain controllers.

      Server 2016 adds the "Expiration time" field in version 2 of this event. 
     </knowledge>
      <description>A member was added to a security-enabled global group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4729</id>  
     <knowledge>
      The user in Subject: removed the user/group/computer in Member: from the Security Global group in Group:.

      In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

      Global means the group can be granted access in any trusting domain but may only have members from its own domain. 

      This event is only logged on domain controllers.
     </knowledge>    
      <description>A member was removed from a security-enabled global group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4730</id> 
     <knowledge>
      The user in Subject: deleted the Security Global group identified in Deleted Group.

      In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

      Global means the group can be granted access in any trusting domain but may only have members from its own domain.

      This event is only logged on domain controllers.
     </knowledge>    
      <description>A security-enabled global group was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4731</id>     
     <knowledge>
      The user in Subject: created a Security Local group identified in New Group.

      This event is logged on domain controllers for Active Directory domain local groups and member computer for local SAM groups.  You can determine if the group is a domain or SAM group by comparing Group Domain: to the Computer: name.  If they match you have a SAM group, if they differ you have a domain group.

    <h3>Active Directory</h3>

      In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

      A domain local group means the group can only be granted access to objects within its domain but can have members from any trusted domain.

    <h3>Local SAM</h3>

      All groups are security groups in the computer's SAM.  Local SAM groups can be granted access to objects on the local computer only but may have members from the local SAM and any trusted domain.
     </knowledge> 
      <description>A security-enabled local group was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4732</id>    
     <knowledge>
      The user in Subject: added the user/group/computer in Member: to the Security Local group in Group:.

      This event is logged on domain controllers for Active Directory domain local groups and member computer for local SAM groups.  You can determine if the group is a domain or SAM group by comparing Group Domain: to the Computer: name.  If they match you have a SAM group, if they differ you have a domain group.

      <h3>Active Directory</h3>

      In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists. A domain local group means the group can only be granted access to objects within its domain but can have members from any trusted domain.

      <h3>Local SAM</h3>

      All groups are security groups in the computer's SAM.  Local SAM groups can be granted access to objects on the local computer only but may have members from the local SAM and any trusted domain.
 
      Server 2016 adds the "Expiration time" field in version 2 of this event. 
     </knowledge> 
      <description>A member was added to a security-enabled local group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4733</id>      
     <knowledge>
        The user in Subject: removed the user/group/computer in Member: to the Security Local group in Group:.

        This event is logged on domain controllers for Active Directory domain local groups and member computer for local SAM groups.  You can determine if the group is a domain or SAM group by comparing Group Domain: to the Computer: name.  If they match you have a SAM group, if they differ you have a domain group.

        <h3>Active Directory</h3>

        In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

        A domain local group means the group can only be granted access to objects within its domain but can have members from any trusted domain.

        <h3>Local SAM</h3>

        All groups are security groups in the computer's SAM.  Local SAM groups can be granted access to objects on the local computer only but may have members from the local SAM and any trusted domain.
     </knowledge> 
      <description>A member was removed from a security-enabled local group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4734</id>   
       <knowledge>
          The user in Subject: deleted the Security Local group identified in Deleted Group.

          This event is logged on domain controllers for Active Directory domain local groups and member computer for local SAM groups.  You can determine if the group is a domain or SAM group by comparing Group Domain: to the Computer: name.  If they match you have a SAM group, if they differ you have a domain group.

        <h3>Active Directory</h3>

          In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

          A domain local group means the group can only be granted access to objects within its domain but can have members from any trusted domain.

        <h3>Local SAM</h3>
        
          All groups are security groups in the computer's SAM.  Local SAM groups can be granted access to objects on the local computer only but may have members from the local SAM and any trusted domain.
     </knowledge>    
      <description>A security-enabled local group was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4735</id>    
            <knowledge>
          The user in Subject: deleted the Security Local group identified in Deleted Group.

          This event is logged on domain controllers for Active Directory domain local groups and member computer for local SAM groups.  You can determine if the group is a domain or SAM group by comparing Group Domain: to the Computer: name.  If they match you have a SAM group, if they differ you have a domain group.

        <h3>Active Directory</h3>

          In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

          A domain local group means the group can only be granted access to objects within its domain but can have members from any trusted domain.

        <h3>Local SAM</h3>
        
          All groups are security groups in the computer's SAM.  Local SAM groups can be granted access to objects on the local computer only but may have members from the local SAM and any trusted domain.
     </knowledge>    
      <description>A security-enabled local group was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4737</id>     
     <knowledge>
      The user in Subject: changed the Security Global group identified in Group:.

      In Active Directory Users and Computers "Security Enabled" groups are simply referred to as Security groups. AD has 2 types of groups: Security and Distribution. Distribution (security disabled) groups are for distribution lists in Exchange and cannot be assigned permissions or rights. Security (security enabled) groups can be used for permissions, rights and as distribution lists.

      Global means the group can be granted access in any trusting domain but may only have members from its own domain.

      This event is only logged on domain controllers.
     </knowledge> 
      <description>A security-enabled global group was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4738</id>
     <knowledge>
      The user identified by Subject: changed the user identified by Target Account:. 

      Attributes show some of the properties that were set at the time the account was changed. 

      This event is logged both for local SAM accounts and domain accounts.

      Depending on what was changed you may see other User Account Management events specific to certain operations like password resets.
     </knowledge>      
      <description>A user account was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4739</id>      
      <description>Domain Policy was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4740</id>      
      <description>A user account was locked out</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4741</id>      
      <description>A computer account was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4742</id>      
      <description>A computer account was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4743</id>      
      <description>A computer account was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4744</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled local group was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4745</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled local group was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4746</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-disabled local group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4747</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-disabled local group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4748</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled local group was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4749</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled global group was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4750</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled global group was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4751</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-disabled global group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4752</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-disabled global group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4753</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled global group was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4754</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled universal group was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4755</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled universal group was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4756</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-enabled universal group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4757</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-enabled universal group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4758</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled universal group was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4759</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled universal group was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4760</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled universal group was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4761</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a security-disabled universal group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4762</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a security-disabled universal group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4763</id>      
      <description>A security-disabled universal group was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4764</id>      
      <description>A groups type was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4765</id>      
      <description>SID History was added to an account</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4766</id>      
      <description>An attempt to add SID History to an account failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4767</id>      
      <description>A user account was unlocked</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4768</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos authentication ticket (TGT) was requested</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4769</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos service ticket was requested</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4770</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos service ticket was renewed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4771</id>      
      <description>Kerberos pre-authentication failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4772</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos authentication ticket request failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4773</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos service ticket request failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4774</id>      
      <description>An account was mapped for logon</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4775</id>      
      <description>An account could not be mapped for logon</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4776</id>      
      <description>The domain controller attempted to validate the credentials for an account</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4777</id>      
      <description>The domain controller failed to validate the credentials for an account</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4778</id>      
      <description>A session was reconnected to a Window Station</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4779</id>      
      <description>A session was disconnected from a Window Station</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4780</id>      
      <description>The ACL was set on accounts which are members of administrators groups</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4781</id>      
      <description>The name of an account was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4782</id>      
      <description>The password hash an account was accessed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4783</id>      
      <description>A basic application group was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4784</id>      
      <description>A basic application group was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4785</id>      
      <description>A member was added to a basic application group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4786</id>      
      <description>A member was removed from a basic application group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4787</id>      
      <description>A non-member was added to a basic application group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4788</id>      
      <description>A non-member was removed from a basic application group..</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4789</id>      
      <description>A basic application group was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4790</id>      
      <description>An LDAP query group was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4791</id>      
      <description>A basic application group was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4792</id>      
      <description>An LDAP query group was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4793</id>      
      <description>The Password Policy Checking API was called</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4794</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to set the Directory Services Restore Mode administrator password</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4797</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to query the existence of a blank password for an account</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4798</id>      
      <description>A user's local group membership was enumerated.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4799</id>      
      <description>A security-enabled local group membership was enumerated</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4800</id>      
      <description>The workstation was locked</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4801</id>      
      <description>The workstation was unlocked</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4802</id>      
      <description>The screen saver was invoked</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4803</id>      
      <description>The screen saver was dismissed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4816</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>RPC detected an integrity violation while decrypting an incoming message</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4817</id>      
      <description>Auditing settings on object were changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4818</id>      
      <description>Proposed Central Access Policy does not grant the same access permissions as the current Central Access Policy</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4819</id>      
      <description>Central Access Policies on the machine have been changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4820</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos Ticket-granting-ticket (TGT) was denied because the device does not meet the access control restrictions</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4821</id>      
      <description>A Kerberos service ticket was denied because the user, device, or both does not meet the access control restrictions</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4822</id>      
      <description>NTLM authentication failed because the account was a member of the Protected User group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4823</id>      
      <description>NTLM authentication failed because access control restrictions are required</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4824</id>      
      <description>Kerberos preauthentication by using DES or RC4 failed because the account was a member of the Protected User group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4825</id>      
      <description>A user was denied the access to Remote Desktop. By default, users are allowed to connect only if they are members of the Remote Desktop Users group or Administrators group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4822</id>      
      <description>NTLM authentication failed because the account was a member of the Protected User group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4823</id>      
      <description>NTLM authentication failed because access control restrictions are required</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4824</id>      
     
    <event>
     <id>4822</id>      
      <description>NTLM authentication failed because the account was a member of the Protected User group</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4823</id>      
      <description>NTLM authentication failed because access control restrictions are required</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4824</id>      
     <id>4826</id>      
      <description>Boot Configuration Data loaded</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4830</id>      
      <description>SID History was removed from an account</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4864</id>      
      <description>A namespace collision was detected</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4865</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A trusted forest information entry was added</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4866</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A trusted forest information entry was removed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4867</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A trusted forest information entry was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4868</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The certificate manager denied a pending certificate request</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4869</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services received a resubmitted certificate request</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4870</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Certificate Services revoked a certificate</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4871</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services received a request to publish the certificate revocation list (CRL)</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4872</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services published the certificate revocation list (CRL)</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4873</id>      
      <description>A certificate request extension changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4874</id>      
      <description>One or more certificate request attributes changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4875</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services received a request to shut down</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4876</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services backup started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4877</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services backup completed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4878</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services restore started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4879</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services restore completed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4880</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4881</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services stopped</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4882</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The security permissions for Certificate Services changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4883</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services retrieved an archived key</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4884</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services imported a certificate into its database</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4885</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The audit filter for Certificate Services changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4886</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services received a certificate request</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4887</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services approved a certificate request and issued a certificate</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4888</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services denied a certificate request</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4889</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services set the status of a certificate request to pending</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4890</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The certificate manager settings for Certificate Services changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4891</id>      
      <description>A configuration entry changed in Certificate Services</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4892</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A property of Certificate Services changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4893</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services archived a key</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4894</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services imported and archived a key</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4895</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services published the CA certificate to Active Directory Domain Services</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4896</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>One or more rows have been deleted from the certificate database</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4897</id>      
      <description>Role separation enabled</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4898</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services loaded a template</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4899</id>      
      <description>A Certificate Services template was updated</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4900</id>      
      <description>Certificate Services template security was updated</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4902</id>      
      <description>The Per-user audit policy table was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4904</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to register a security event source</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4905</id>      
      <description>An attempt was made to unregister a security event source</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4906</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The CrashOnAuditFail value has changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4907</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Auditing settings on object were changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4908</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Special Groups Logon table modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4909</id>      
      <description>The local policy settings for the TBS were changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4910</id>      
      <description>The group policy settings for the TBS were changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4911</id>      
      <description>Resource attributes of the object were changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4912</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Per User Audit Policy was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4913</id>      
      <description>Central Access Policy on the object was changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4928</id>      
      <description>An Active Directory replica source naming context was established</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4929</id>      
      <description>An Active Directory replica source naming context was removed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4930</id>      
      <description>An Active Directory replica source naming context was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4931</id>      
      <description>An Active Directory replica destination naming context was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4932</id>      
      <description>Synchronization of a replica of an Active Directory naming context has begun</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4933</id>      
      <description>Synchronization of a replica of an Active Directory naming context has ended</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4934</id>      
      <description>Attributes of an Active Directory object were replicated</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4935</id>      
      <description>Replication failure begins</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4936</id>      
      <description>Replication failure ends</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4937</id>      
      <description>A lingering object was removed from a replica</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4944</id>      
      <description>The following policy was active when the Windows Firewall started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4945</id>      
      <description>A rule was listed when the Windows Firewall started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4946</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to Windows Firewall exception list. A rule was added</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4947</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to Windows Firewall exception list. A rule was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4948</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to Windows Firewall exception list. A rule was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4949</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall settings were restored to the default values</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4950</id>      
      <description>A Windows Firewall setting has changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4951</id>      
      <description>A rule has been ignored because its major version number was not recognized by Windows Firewall</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4952</id>      
      <description>Parts of a rule have been ignored because its minor version number was not recognized by Windows Firewall</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4953</id>      
      <description>A rule has been ignored by Windows Firewall because it could not parse the rule</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4954</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall Group Policy settings has changed. The new settings have been applied</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4956</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall has changed the active profile</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4957</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall did not apply the following rule</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4958</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall did not apply the following rule because the rule referred to items not configured on this computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4960</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec dropped an inbound packet that failed an integrity check</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4961</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec dropped an inbound packet that failed a replay check</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4962</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec dropped an inbound packet that failed a replay check</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4963</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec dropped an inbound clear text packet that should have been secured</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4964</id>      
      <description>Special groups have been assigned to a new logon</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4965</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec received a packet from a remote computer with an incorrect Security Parameter Index (SPI).</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4976</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>During Main Mode negotiation, IPsec received an invalid negotiation packet.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4977</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>During Quick Mode negotiation, IPsec received an invalid negotiation packet.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4978</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>During Extended Mode negotiation, IPsec received an invalid negotiation packet.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4979</id>      
      <description>IPsec Main Mode and Extended Mode security associations were established.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4980</id>      
      <description>IPsec Main Mode and Extended Mode security associations were established</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4981</id>      
      <description>IPsec Main Mode and Extended Mode security associations were established</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4982</id>      
      <description>IPsec Main Mode and Extended Mode security associations were established</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4983</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>An IPsec Extended Mode negotiation failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4984</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>An IPsec Extended Mode negotiation failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>4985</id>      
      <description>The state of a transaction has changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5024</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service has started successfully</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5025</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service has been stopped</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5027</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service was unable to retrieve the security policy from the local storage</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5028</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service was unable to parse the new security policy.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5029</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service failed to initialize the driver</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5030</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service failed to start</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5031</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Service blocked an application from accepting incoming connections on the network.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5032</id>      
      <description>Windows Firewall was unable to notify the user that it blocked an application from accepting incoming connections on the network</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5033</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Driver has started successfully</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5034</id>      
      <description>The Windows Firewall Driver has been stopped</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5035</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Driver failed to start</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5037</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>The Windows Firewall Driver detected critical runtime error. Terminating</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5038</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Code integrity determined that the image hash of a file is not valid</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5039</id>      
      <description>A registry key was virtualized.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5040</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. An Authentication Set was added.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5041</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. An Authentication Set was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5042</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. An Authentication Set was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5043</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Connection Security Rule was added</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5044</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Connection Security Rule was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5045</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Connection Security Rule was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5046</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Crypto Set was added</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5047</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Crypto Set was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5048</id>      
      <description>A change has been made to IPsec settings. A Crypto Set was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5049</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Security Association was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5050</id>      
      <description>An attempt to programmatically disable the Windows Firewall using a call to INetFwProfile.FirewallEnabled(FALSE</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5051</id>      
      <description>A file was virtualized</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5056</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic self test was performed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5057</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic primitive operation failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5058</id>      
      <description>Key file operation</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5059</id>      
      <description>Key migration operation</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5060</id>      
      <description>Verification operation failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5061</id>      
      <description>Cryptographic operation</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5062</id>      
      <description>A kernel-mode cryptographic self test was performed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5063</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic provider operation was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5064</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic context operation was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5065</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic context modification was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5066</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function operation was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5067</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function modification was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5068</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function provider operation was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5069</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function property operation was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5070</id>      
      <description>A cryptographic function property operation was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5071</id>      
      <description>Key access denied by Microsoft key distribution service</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5120</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>OCSP Responder Service Started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5121</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>OCSP Responder Service Stopped</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5122</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A Configuration entry changed in the OCSP Responder Service</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5123</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>A configuration entry changed in the OCSP Responder Service</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5124</id>      
      <description>A security setting was updated on OCSP Responder Service</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5125</id>      
      <description>A request was submitted to OCSP Responder Service</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5126</id>      
      <description>Signing Certificate was automatically updated by the OCSP Responder Service</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5127</id>      
      <description>The OCSP Revocation Provider successfully updated the revocation information</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5136</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5137</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was created</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5138</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was undeleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5139</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was moved</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5140</id>      
      <description>A network share object was accessed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5141</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was deleted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5142</id>      
      <description>A network share object was added.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5143</id>      
      <description>A network share object was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5144</id>      
      <description>A network share object was deleted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5145</id>      
      <description>A network share object was checked to see whether client can be granted desired access</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5146</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has blocked a packet</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5147</id>      
      <description>A more restrictive Windows Filtering Platform filter has blocked a packet</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5148</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has detected a DoS attack and entered a defensive mode; packets associated with this attack will be discarded.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5149</id>      
      <description>The DoS attack has subsided and normal processing is being resumed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5150</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has blocked a packet.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5151</id>      
      <description>A more restrictive Windows Filtering Platform filter has blocked a packet.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5152</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform blocked a packet</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5153</id>      
      <description>A more restrictive Windows Filtering Platform filter has blocked a packet</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5154</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has permitted an application or service to listen on a port for incoming connections</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5155</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has blocked an application or service from listening on a port for incoming connections</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5156</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has allowed a connection</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5157</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has blocked a connection</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5158</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has permitted a bind to a local port</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5159</id>      
      <description>The Windows Filtering Platform has blocked a bind to a local port</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5168</id>      
      <description>Spn check for SMB/SMB2 fails.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5169</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5170</id>      
      <description>A directory service object was modified during a background cleanup task</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5376</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Credential Manager credentials were backed up</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5377</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Credential Manager credentials were restored from a backup</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5378</id>      
      <description>The requested credentials delegation was disallowed by policy</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5379</id>      
      <description>Credential Manager credentials were read</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5380</id>      
      <description>Vault Find Credential</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5381</id>      
      <description>Vault credentials were read</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5382</id>      
      <description>Vault credentials were read</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5440</id>      
      <description>The following callout was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5441</id>      
      <description>The following filter was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5442</id>      
      <description>The following provider was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5443</id>      
      <description>The following provider context was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5444</id>      
      <description>The following sub-layer was present when the Windows Filtering Platform Base Filtering Engine started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5446</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform callout has been changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5447</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform filter has been changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5448</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform provider has been changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5449</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform provider context has been changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5450</id>      
      <description>A Windows Filtering Platform sub-layer has been changed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5451</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Quick Mode security association was established</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5452</id>      
      <description>An IPsec Quick Mode security association ended</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5453</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>An IPsec negotiation with a remote computer failed because the IKE and AuthIP IPsec Keying Modules (IKEEXT) service is not started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5456</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine applied Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5457</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to apply Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5458</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine applied locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5459</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to apply locally cached copy of Active Directory storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5460</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine applied local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5461</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to apply local registry storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5462</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to apply some rules of the active IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5463</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the active IPsec policy and detected no changes</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5464</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the active IPsec policy, detected changes, and applied them to IPsec Services</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5465</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine received a control for forced reloading of IPsec policy and processed the control successfully</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5466</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the Active Directory IPsec policy, determined that Active Directory cannot be reached, and will use the cached copy of the Active Directory IPsec policy instead</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5467</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the Active Directory IPsec policy, determined that Active Directory can be reached, and found no changes to the policy</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5468</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine polled for changes to the Active Directory IPsec policy, determined that Active Directory can be reached, found changes to the policy, and applied those changes</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5471</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine loaded local storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5472</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to load local storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5473</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine loaded directory storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5474</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to load directory storage IPsec policy on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5477</id>      
      <description>PAStore Engine failed to add quick mode filter</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5478</id>      
      <description>IPsec Services has started successfully</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5479</id>      
      <description>IPsec Services has been shut down successfully</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5480</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services failed to get the complete list of network interfaces on the computer</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5483</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services failed to initialize RPC server. IPsec Services could not be started</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5484</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services has experienced a critical failure and has been shut down</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5485</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>IPsec Services failed to process some IPsec filters on a plug-and-play event for network interfaces</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5632</id>      
      <description>A request was made to authenticate to a wireless network</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5633</id>      
      <description>A request was made to authenticate to a wired network</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5712</id>      
      <description>A Remote Procedure Call (RPC) was attempted</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5888</id>      
      <description>An object in the COM+ Catalog was modified</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5889</id>      
      <description>An object was deleted from the COM+ Catalog</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>5890</id>      
      <description>An object was added to the COM+ Catalog</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6144</id>      
      <description>Security policy in the group policy objects has been applied successfully</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6145</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>One or more errors occured while processing security policy in the group policy objects</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6272</id>      
      <description>Network Policy Server granted access to a user</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6273</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server denied access to a user</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6274</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server discarded the request for a user</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6275</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server discarded the accounting request for a user</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6276</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server quarantined a user</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6277</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server granted access to a user but put it on probation because the host did not meet the defined health policy</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6278</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server granted full access to a user because the host met the defined health policy</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6279</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server locked the user account due to repeated failed authentication attempts</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6280</id>      
     <knowledge>Criticality: Medium — investigate only on unexpected occurrence or significant deviation from baseline volume within a measured period.</knowledge>
      <description>Network Policy Server unlocked the user account</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6281</id>      
      <description>Code Integrity determined that the page hashes of an image file are not valid...</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6400</id>      
      <description>BranchCache: Received an incorrectly formatted response while discovering availability of content.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6401</id>      
      <description>BranchCache: Received invalid data from a peer. Data discarded.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6402</id>      
      <description>BranchCache: The message to the hosted cache offering it data is incorrectly formatted.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6403</id>      
      <description>BranchCache: The hosted cache sent an incorrectly formatted response to the client's message to offer it data.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6404</id>      
      <description>BranchCache: Hosted cache could not be authenticated using the provisioned SSL certificate.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6405</id>      
      <description>BranchCache: %2 instance(s) of event id %1 occurred.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6406</id>      
      <description>%1 registered to Windows Firewall to control filtering for the following:</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6407</id>      
      <description>%1</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6408</id>      
      <description>Registered product %1 failed and Windows Firewall is now controlling the filtering for %2.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6409</id>      
      <description>BranchCache: A service connection point object could not be parsed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6410</id>      
      <description>Code integrity determined that a file does not meet the security requirements to load into a process. This could be due to the use of shared sections or other issues</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6416</id>      
      <description>A new external device was recognized by the system.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6417</id>      
      <description>The FIPS mode crypto selftests succeeded</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6418</id>      
      <description>The FIPS mode crypto selftests failed</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6419</id>      
      <description>A request was made to disable a device</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6420</id>      
      <description>A device was disabled</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6421</id>      
      <description>A request was made to enable a device</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6422</id>      
      <description>A device was enabled</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6423</id>      
      <description>The installation of this device is forbidden by system policy</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>6424</id>      
      <description>The installation of this device was allowed, after having previously been forbidden by policy</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>8191</id>      
      <description>Highest System-Defined Audit Message Value</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>16002</id>      
      <description>Closing a TCP socket with local port number 55157 in process 5284 is taking longer than expected. The local port number may not be available until the close operation is completed. This happens typically due to misbehaving network drivers. Ensure latest updates are installed for Windows and any third-party networking software including NIC drivers, firewalls, or other security products. </description>       
     </event>   

    <event>
     <id>24577</id>      
      <description>Encryption of volume started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24578</id>      
      <description>Encryption of volume stopped.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24579</id>      
      <description>Encryption of volume completed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24580</id>      
      <description>Decryption of volume started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24581</id>      
      <description>Decryption of volume stopped.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24582</id>      
      <description>Decryption of volume completed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24583</id>      
      <description>Conversion worker thread for volume started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24584</id>      
      <description>Conversion worker thread for volume temporarily stopped.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24588</id>      
      <description>The conversion operation on volume %2 encountered a bad sector error. Please validate the data on this volume.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24595</id>      
      <description>Volume %2 contains bad clusters. These clusters will be skipped during conversion.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>24621</id>      
      <description>Initial state check: Rolling volume conversion transaction on %2.</description>       
     </event>

    <event>
     <id>550</id>      
      <description>Possible denial-of-service (DoS) attack.</description>       
     </event>


     <event>
     <id>N/A</id>      
      <description>A handle to an object was requested.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>N/A</id>      
      <description>Object open for delete.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>N/A</id>      
      <description>User Account Type Changed.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>N/A</id>      
      <description>IPsec policy agent started.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>N/A</id>      
      <description>IPsec policy agent disabled.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>N/A</id>      
      <description>IPsec policy agent.</description>       
     </event>
     
    <event>
     <id>N/A</id>      
      <description>IPsec policy agent encountered a potential serious failure.</description>       
     </event>
<eventIdListings>